ht.com.au 2019-09-01

# Security &amp; Privacy Policy | Purchasing Information | ht.com.au

Read about our commitment to ensuring the privacy of your information. If you can't find the information you need, please use the [Make an Enquiry](https://www.ht.com.au/form/enquiry/forms.hts) page or phone **1300 13 9999** and get help from a Customer Service representative. 

#### How We Handle Customer Information

Harris Technology is committed to client service and this policy outlines our ongoing obligations to you in respect to how we manage your Personal Information. We have adopted the 10 National Privacy Principles (NPPs) contained in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (the Privacy Act). The NPPs came into effect on 21 December 2001. The NPPs govern the way in which we collect, use, disclose, store, secure and dispose of your Personal Information. A copy of the National Privacy Principles may be obtained from the website of The Office of the Federal Privacy Commissioner at www.privacy.gov.au. 

### What is Personal Information and why do we collect it?

Personal Information is information or an opinion that identifies an individual. Examples of Personal Information we collect include: names, addresses, email addresses, phone and fax numbers. This Personal Information is obtained in many ways including interviews, correspondence, by telephone and fax, by email, via our website www.ht.com.au and from third parties. We collect your Personal Information for the primary purpose of providing our services to our clients, and for our own marketing. We may also use your Personal Information for secondary purposes closely related to the primary purpose, in circumstances where you would reasonably expect such use or disclosure. You may unsubscribe from our mailing/marketing lists at any time; all you need to do is let us know. When we collect Personal Information we will, where appropriate and where possible, explain to you why we are collecting the information and how we plan to use it. 

#### What information do we collect?

When you visit the Harris Technology website you may provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis, and Web site use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our Web site.

We do not use cookies for marketing, promotional or advertising purposes, nor do we use cookies to track your Internet activity before or after you leave Harris Technology. Any activity while you are at ht.com.au may be monitored.

#### 1\. Personal Information You Choose to Provide

**Registration Information** \- When you register for an account or place an order for our products you will provide us information about yourself.

**Credit Card Information** \- When placing an order you may need to give personal information and authorisation to obtain information from various credit services. For example, you may need to provide the following information:

-Name, mailing address, email address, credit card number, name on credit card, credit card billing address, business and/or home phone number

**Email Information** \- If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received by mail and telephone.

#### 2\. Web Site Use Information

**HT.com.au** utilises a standard internet technology called â€œcookiesâ€ (see below for more information) and web server log files to collect information about how our Web site is used. Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Web site, and the Web sites visited just before and just after our Web site. Generally speaking this service is anonymous and used only for statistical analysis. When you register for an account or place an order for our products you will provide us information about yourself.

We do not want to send emails to you if you would prefer not to receive them. Therefore, every email provides a way for you to unsubscribe from future emails. In addition, you can visit our Subscription Centre to manage your subscription. We also have administrative procedures in place to remove email addresses and domains that consistently send failure messages to our email servers.

#### How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?

Harris Technology uses personal information for the purposes of administering our business activities, providing the products requested by our customers, to process customer payments, to monitor the use of our services, for marketing and promotional efforts and to improve our content and service offerings, and customise our siteâ€™s content, layout, services and for other lawful purposes. These uses improve our business and better tailor it to meet your needs.

Furthermore, such information may be shared with others on an aggregate basis. Personally identifiable information or business information will not be shared with parties except as required by law.

#### What Are Cookies?

Cookies are small files which are stored on a user's computer. They are designed to hold a modest amount of data specific to a particular client and website, and can be accessed either by the web server or the client computer. This allows the server to deliver a page tailored to a particular user, or the page itself can contain some script which is aware of the data in the cookie and so is able to carry information from one visit to the website (or related site) to the next.

Once the cookie has been read by the code on the server or client computer, the data can be retrieved and used to customise the web page appropriately.

Cookies are a convenient way to carry information from one session on a website to another, or between sessions on related websites, without having to burden a server machine with massive amounts of data storage. Essentially, it allows us to better serve our website visitors with relevant information and content, whilst optimising our own practises.

#### Sharing and Selling Information

We do not and will not share, sell, lend or lease any of the information that uniquely identify a subscriber or customer (such as email addresses or personal details) with anyone except to the extent it is necessary to process transactions or provide services that you have requested.

Once the cookie has been read by the code on the server or client computer, the data can be retrieved and used to customise the web page appropriately.

#### How Can You Access and Correct Your Information?

NPP 6 provides you with the right to access the Personal Information which we hold about you and to update and/or correct it, subject to certain exceptions. If you wish to access your Personal Information, please make out your request to us in writing.

#### What About Legally Compelled Disclosure of Information?

Your Personal Information may be disclosed in a number of circumstances including the following: 

\- third parties where you consent to the use or disclosure; and 

\- where required or authorised by law. 

#### What About Other Web Sites Linked to Our Web Site?

We are not responsible for the practices employed by Web sites linked to or from our Web site or the information or content contained therein. Often links to other Web sites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our Web site.

Please remember that when you use a link to go from our website to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other web site, including web sites which have a link on our Website, is subject to that websiteâ€™s own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

#### Your Consent

By using our Web site you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to amend this privacy policy at any time with or without notice.

#### Security of Personal Information

Your Personal Information is stored in a manner that reasonably protects it from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

When your Personal Information is no longer needed for the purpose for which it was obtained, we will take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify your Personal Information. However, most of the Personal Information is or will be stored in client files which will be kept by us for a minimum of 7 years.

#### Maintaining the Quality of your Personal Information

It is an important part of providing our services to you that your Personal Information is up to date. National Privacy Policy dictates that we take reasonable steps to make sure that your Personal Information is accurate, complete and up-to-date.

#### Complaints

You can lodge a complaint with us about any breach of our Privacy Policy and our privacy obligations to you by contacting feedback@ht.com.au
